

# **Jayakumar Virushabadass**

Full Stack Developer, Chennai, India.

Phone: +91 9500253553

Email: vjayakumarjk@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jayakumar-virushabadass

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jay-kumar-jk">https://github.com/jay-kumar-jk</a> Website: <a href="https://jay-kumar-jk.github.io">https://jay-kumar-jk.github.io</a>





Senior Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience in overseeing all aspects of the Software Development Life Cycle. Proficient in Software Development using .NET Core, Python, Angular and Database Management.

AWS Certified Developer Associate involved in developing Microservices Serverless applications using AWS Cloud Services

## Summary

- Net core/Microservices/AWS/Python Professional with 6+ years of experience.
- Experience in developing microservices serverless application using cutting edge technologies.
- Well-versed in requirement gathering and analysis.
- Experienced in client coordination from both onsite (Leeds, UK) and offshore.
- Adapt in Software development and enhancements using Agile and Waterfall methodology.

Skill Summary	
Domain	Healthcare, Ecommerce, Banking
Programming Languages / Tools / DB / Packages / Framework	C#, .Net Core, Python, ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC, ADO.NET, Entity Framework, REST API, REST/SOAP web services, Windows Form, WPF, Web Form, MOQ Framework, NUNIT Docker, Containerized application, Kubernetes (Beginner) MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL Angular, React JS (Beginner), JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Git/GitHub, Azure DevOps, JIRA
AWS Cloud	EC2, S3, Lambda, DynamoDB, RDS, API Gateway, SNS, SQS, SES, RDS, Cognito, ECS, ECR, EKS, Cloudwatch, Secrets Manager, Cloudformation

## **Professional Certifications/ Trainings**

- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications (70-486)

## **Educational Qualification**

Bachelor Of Engineering in Computer Science (B.E) with 7.7 CGPA – 2011-2015 Anna University, Chennai, India.

## **Experience Summary**

# Senior Engineer – Cloud Services and Software

L&T Infotech / Chennai, India / July 2021 - Present

- Developed Microservices serverless applications using .NET Core, Angular, PostgreSQL and deployed into AWS ECS.
- Formulated standard and central logging module and integrated it to Cloudwatch.
- Implemented SSO Authentication using Angular MSAL, API authorization (.Net Core) using Azure AD Identity Server.
- Managed Azure App registrations and user roles for application in Azure user groups, implemented application functionality using Microsoft Graph API.
- Involved in Devops activity by configuring **Azure CI/CD pipelines**, creating, and pushing docker images to AWS ECR.
- Involved in migrating On-Premises application to AWS which reduced product costs by 30%.
- Code review, Unit testing, Peer testing and fixing SonarQube/Checkmarx vulnerabilities issues.

### **Senior Associate**

Emis Health India Pvt Ltd / Chennai, India / July 2018 – July 2021

- Developed Serverless applications using GO Lang, AWS Lambda, DynamoDB, AWS Cognito and API Gateway.
- Designed and integrated front-end application using React JS and deployed using S3 static website hosting.
- Designed and developed application authentication using AWS Cognito.
- Accomplished a POC on maintaining Test cases for each module of an application in a Single repository
- Developed, Managed and Enhanced various modules in Health Care windows application using C#, WPF and MS SQL Server.
- Involved in Peer testing, Unit testing, and fixing SonarQube vulnerabilities issue.
- Engaged in sprint planning, agile activities, code reviews and contribute to sprint velocity.
- Mentored new joiners and freshers, actively involved in knowledge sharing session.

## **Associate Consultant – Technology**

Virtusa Consulting Software Services Pvt Ltd / Chennai, India / Sep 2015 – July 2018

- Involved in transitioning application from On-Premises to AWS by lift and shift Policy.
- Developed Web application using Asp.net MVC 5 and Oracle SQL Server.
- Developed an Ecommerce application to maintain Rebate and Billing of customers in Queue basis using AWS services such as SQS and SNS.
- Enhanced the performance and Delivered ECommerce application with improvement in performance by 20%.
- Understanding the functional specifications and enhanced various work stream codes based on the requirement.
- Worked in App Support team providing code fixes and data fixes in production.
- Involved in unit testing (Nunit) and improved the code coverage to up to 85%.

#### **Accomplishments**

- Star Team of the Quarter Q3 2019
- Extra Mile Award Feb 2017

## Interests

- Curious in solving Sudoku
- Playing Cricket